# Marcos Acosta

Homestead, Florida, United States

marcos87@gmail.com

5743270035

linkedin.com/in/marcosgacosta

# **Summary**

+10 years of professional experience using IT to solve businesses problems.

Throughout the years, I have taken diverse roles such as Support Engineer (hands-on experience configuring, and troubleshooting IP and Optical Networks), Business Analyst, Network Specialist, Tech Instructor, and Implementation analyst in software projects. This diverse experience helps me to engage with complex technical problems with a business-oriented mindset.

Currently, I am looking for opportunities to help organizations implement and design their DevOps and Cloud migration and support strategies.

Follow my journey as I learn new things here: https://github.com/marcosgacosta

### **Experience**

# Cloud Engineer

binbash

Dec 2023 - Present (1 month)

Our focus is on creating reusable, high-quality AWS Cloud Infrastructure code, through our core components:

- ▶# Reference Architecture for AWS
- ▶# Infrastructure as Code (IaC) Library
- ▶# Leverage CLI

Because all the code and modules are already built, we can get your project up and running on AWS up to 10x faster than a consulting company (# typically in just a few weeks!).



#### **Senior Pastor**

Homestead Mennonite Church

Mar 2022 - Dec 2023 (1 year 10 months)

Responsible for the following areas: leadership development, facility management, project management, change management, coordinating staff, and budgeting.

# **\*** Bookstore Manager

**Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary** 

Aug 2019 - Apr 2021 (1 year 9 months)

- Managed inventory and fulfilled +100 orders.
- Generated sales over \$6600 in merchandise.

# **X** IT & AV Technical Support

**Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary** 

Aug 2018 - Mar 2021 (2 years 8 months)

Managed IT and AV needs for seminary events.



### Implementation Engineer (Network)

#### Comarch

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 8 months)

- SME and client single point of contact for network technologies (MW, IP and optical) to implement Comarch OSS for Telefonica Argentina.
- Successfully implemented the Next Generation Network Planning program which scope was DWDM, SONET, Microwaves links and IP devices, which included gathering requirements, designing solutions, delivering trainings and presentations, and supporting change management to go live.
- Promoted from Business Analyst to Stream Leader within the first year.



#### Network Support Engineer

#### Claro Argentina

Nov 2011 - Dec 2016 (5 years 2 months)

- Managed, monitored and troubleshot different network technologies: Fiber Optics, RF Links, Satellite Links. IP/MPLS, SONET, DWDM), on a multivendor mobile and ISP network (Ciena, Nokia, ZTE, Huawei, Cisco, Tellabs, Siemens) covering Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay.
- Provided technical support to field operations for installation, configuration, migration, incident resolution and change management activities.
- Provided training to +30 NOC Analysts: "Architecture and concepts of SONET and DWDM" and "Introducing IP-RAN Technology"
- Provisioned +500 network services over IPRAN, SONET/SDH, MW and DWDM networks.
- Member of the team that improved response time by reducing tickets from an average of +2000 on queue to an average of 10.

#### Prive Test Technician

#### CelPlan de Argentina

Jun 2011 - Nov 2011 (6 months)

Configuration of drive test equipment.

- Measurement taking with drive test software (Temps, Probe, Xcal).
- Uploading of measurements within established deadlines.
- Detection of network problems in the field.
- Direct communication with project coordination in case of incidents.

### Technical Support Analyst

#### Jazztel

Feb 2011 - Jun 2011 (5 months)

Support and troubleshooting residential customers for voice and internet services.

#### **Education**



#### Instituto Universitario Aeronáutico

Engineer's degree, Telecommunications

2006 - 2016

Thesis: Analysis and description of a SONET Network adapted to carry IP traffic required by Nodes B in a 3G System.



Certificate, DevOps Jun 2023 - Mar 2024

## \* Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary

Master of Divinity 2018 - 2021

### **Licenses & Certifications**

4A0-101 Interior Routing Protocols // Network Routing Specialist II - Nokia SRC195848

Network Routing Specialist I - Nokia
Certification ID: 7142

- **TOEFL iBT** ETS
- Google Project Management Certificate Coursera
- AWS Cloud Quest: Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS Knowledge: Cloud Essentials Amazon Web Services (AWS)

#### **Skills**

Terraform • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Customer Service • Amazon EC2 • Amazon S3 • High Availability (HA) • Budgeting • Leadership • Kubernetes • Agile Project Management